Wolf, William B. Papers 6305
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
William B. Wolf Papers
1944-2004
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wolf, William B.
6305
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Papers.
7000252
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. MIles, March 07, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 07, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Arbitrator, labor mediator and attorney; visiting professor, New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University. Wolf served as permanent arbitrator between the New York City Board of Education and the United Federation of Teachers; New York City and the American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME); the New York City Off-Track Betting Corp. and AFSCME; New York State and AFSCME; the State University of New York and the Senate Professional Association; A. Goodman and the American Bakery and Confectionery Workers' Union; and between the Simmons Company and the Upholsterers International Union. Wolf also served as impartial chairman for American Airlines and the Transport Workers Union of America; the men's shirt industry and the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; and the Brooklyn Union Gas Company and the Transport Workers Union of America.
Born May 6, 1909. Attended Cornell University (B.A. 1930; LL.B. 1932).
Formerly labor mediator, New York State Board of Meidation; labor relations examiner, N.Y.S. Labor Relations Board.
Affiliated with National Academy of Arbitrators (board of governors 1971-; regional chairman 1967-1968); Industrial Relations Research Association; Society for Professionals in Dispute Resolution; New York Bar Association. On rosters of American Arbitration Association, Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, National Mediation Board, New York State Board of Mediation, New Jersey State Board of Mediation, New York Public Employment Relations Board, New Jersey Public Employment Relations Commission.
Arbitrator under contract for N.Y. City Board of Education and UFT; City of New York and District Council 37; OTB and DC37; N.Y. State and Council 82, AFSCME: State University of New York and Senate Professional Association; Metropolitan New York Milk Industry and IBT; New Rochelle Board of Education and UFT; A. Goodman & Sons and BCWU; Metropolitan Association of Optical Wholesalers and IUE; Simons Co. and Local 420, UIU.
Impartial Chairman; American Airlines and TWU, Men's Shirt Industry and ACWA; Brooklyn Union Gas and TWU; Williams Press and Pressmen's Union; Hiring Hall & Club Employees Union (Local 16); Westchester County Laundry Board of Trade and Local 335 IBT: Rochdale Village, Inc. and Local 90 Public Service Union; Ossining Board of Education and Ossining Teachers Association; Schwartz Laboratories, Inc. and Oil, Chemical and Atomic Workers; Ross Oil Term. Corp., Howard Fuel Corp. & Local 365 UAW.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6305 AV: William B. Wolf Audio-Visual 6305 P: William B. Wolf Photographs 6138: William B. Wolf Additional Papers
Personnel management; Organizational behavior; Wolf, William B.
7000252
- Chris Argyris. Field Theory as a Basis for Scholarly Consulting, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  The Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues. Journal of Social Issues.
- Banks. The Case for Communism. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Erik H. Erikson. Insight and Responsibility, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Lectures on the Ethical Implications of Psychoanalytic Insight
- Harold Smiddy, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Correspondence. Includes biography by Ronald Greenwood.
- R. Walzer. Galen on Medical Experience, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series Daze of the Dean
  - Volume 1. [folder 1 of 2], 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Participant observer study of Paul Cone and Robert Dockson as Dean of Business and Industrial Management at the University of Southern California.
  - Volume 1. [folder 2 of 2], 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Volume 2. [folder 1 of 2], 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Volume 2. [folder 2 of 2], 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Management and Consulting (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Notes for expanded edition
- Organizational Diagnosis for Consultants and Managers, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Article and notes
- Personnel. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Notes
- The Theory of Management., 2004 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Handwritten article.
- Understanding Organizations and Management., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Course materials and notes
- Understanding Complex Organizations. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Handwritten and typescript portions of a book. Includes diary.